各位观众 即将登场的是
Well, folks there he is,
皮尔特沃夫拳击联盟的蝶量级冠军
the butterflyweight champion of the Piltover Boxing League,
古斯塔夫·“铁下巴”·乔勒
Gustove "The Scowler" Jowler!
? I'm at the bottom It's a long way down ?
? I'm on the bend And it's a long way round ?
? There's no way out Of what I'm talking about
? 'Cause I'm down and out I'm down and I'm out! ?
? I'm in the grave... ?
? For all these reasons That I'm talking about ?
? Your money face can't save me now ?
? I'm in the grave I'm in the underground ?
? You can't redeem us I'm the only child ?
? For all the reasons That I'm talking about ?
? I'm down and out I'm down and I'm out! ?
? Lock me up I cannot take it ?
? Lock me up I've already lost ?
? Lock me up I'm gonna chance it ?
? Throw my cocktail Molotov ?
? Lock me up I cannot take it! ?
? Lock me up I've already lost! ?
? Lock me up I'm gonna chance it! ?
? Throw my cocktail Molotov! ?
? Lock me up I cannot take it! ?
? Lock me up I'm gonna chance it! ?
? Throw my cocktail Molotov ?
混得不错
Looking good, sis.
姐姐
喂 你先别...
Wait, just--
你的话我一个字都不想听
I don't wanna hear another word
你最好闭嘴
out of your mouth.
是范德尔
It's Vander.
少拿你那一套耍我 省省吧你
I'm not falling for another one of your tricks.
范德尔 他还活着
He's... alive.
编瞎话你真是张口就来啊
We both know that's bullshit.
他需要我们的帮助
He needs our help.
你信我一次
I can prove it.
? I wake up to the sounds Of the silence that allows ?
? For my mind to run around With my ear up to the ground ?
? I'm searching to behold The stories that are told ?
? When my back is to the world That was smiling when I turned ?
? Tell you you're the greatest ?
? But once you turn, they hate us ?
? Oh, the misery ?
? Everybody wants to be my enemy ?
? Oh, spare the sympathy ?
? Pray it away, I swear I'll never be a saint, no way ?
? My enemy ?
? Pray it away, I swear I'll never be a saint ?
? Look out for yourself ?
《英雄联盟:双城之战》
第二季第五集
本WEB版外挂字幕由  风吹来的那片云  双语合并
和平接管维持了这么多个月
Months of peacekeeping occupation.
进行了那么多次清剿
Countless operations.
付出了那么多的心血和代价
Oceans of sweat and tears.
还以为跟底城这段恩怨 可以画上句号了
I'd begun to think we might finally see an end to Zaun's perverse abominations.
我可真是蠢到家了
How foolish was I?
那怪物是冲你来的
The beast came for you.
是你把它召唤来的
It was summoned by you.
以我的经验看
In my experience,
面对指控 有罪的人往往选择沉默
only guilty men answer accusations with silence.
以我的经验看
In my experience,
有权的人多少都有罪
no one in power is innocent.
这座监狱底下还有一些牢房
There are cells buried deep within this prison
那里伸手不见五指 连呼吸都成问题
so devoid of light and fresh air
更别谈什么基本的生存保障
and all basic human considerations that up till now,
本来已经被我禁用了
I have forbidden their use.
不想让自己后半辈子 在那种地方过活的话
If you do not want to waste away the remainder of your days in one of these,
你的选择只有一个
you have one recourse.
说吧 该怎么追捕那头怪物
Tell us everything we need to know
说仔细点儿
to hunt down this beast.
你把心急写在了脸上
Your youth betrays you.
耐心是被岁月磨出来的
Patience is a product of age.
你看 我就是个活生生的例子
Both of which I possess in abundance.
这一次是你最后的机会
This is your final chance.
快说你在谋划什么
Tell me what you were planning.
还有 金克丝都干了什么
How was Jinx involved?
那你就等着烂在这儿吧
You will rot in here.
依罗拉
Elora?
黑色玫瑰
Black Rose.
不知道这个地方你待得习不习惯
Hope you find these quarters to your liking.
我总想换个地方
They still haven't replied
可他们却一直不答应
to my requests for a transfer.
是谁在那儿
Who's there?
我就快忘了自己是谁了
Not sure I know anymore.
把咱们请到这儿的人
Our hosts have a way
总有办法把你脑子搅乱
of scrambling your omelet.
他们害死了我的朋友
They killed my friend.
当时依罗拉就在那儿 然后就...
Elora was there. And then...
依罗拉
Elora!
旧世界的掌管者
Ah. The stewards of the old world
一有机会就喜欢 小小地炫耀一下他们的能耐
are always keen to give you a glimpse of their might.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
据我所知
Near as I can tell,
叫窥视之地
an Oculorum.
有传说记载 这个地方
According to legend,
起初是人们为了 禁锢伪先知专门建造的
the ancients built specialized chambers to seal away false prophets.
要我说
But if you ask me,
这就是孔雀王子们 为了捉弄人们设下的虚幻牢笼
they're just the fancy pits peacock princes like to toss their friends into.
什么孔雀王子
Peacock princes?
抱歉 我们家开玩笑的说法
Sorry, just an old family joke.
是指那些有艺术天赋的统治者
You know, the kind of rulers with an artistic flair.
站到亮处来
Step into the light.
基诺
Kino?
是我啊 哥哥
It's me, brother.
梅尔
Mel.
你都这么大了
You've grown up.
他们到底还是找上你了
I'd hoped they'd never come for you.
我就是在这儿把他跟丢的
This is where I lost him.
好看吧 而且还没有毒
Cool, huh? Not even toxic.
应该没有
Pretty sure.
范德尔为什么要 一路往这么个地方跑
Why would Vander be all the way down here?
我哪知道 你自己去问他呀
Beats me. Ask him yourself.
你什么时候能承认 这只是你的妄想而已
When will you admit that this is just one of your fantasies?
你爱妄想这事儿应该 不想让这孩子知道吧
Or do you not want the kid to know how delusional you are?
她以前可不是这样的
She wasn't always like this.
以前的她比现在好多了
She actually used to be pretty cool,
都赖我 老是对她动手
before I kicked her butt.
我说什么来着 又妄想了
See what I mean? Delusional.
你跑去跟杀了 老爸老妈的皮城走狗混在一起
Wish I was just seeing things when you decided
这事最好也是我妄想出来的
to throw in with the Piltie goons who murdered Mom and Dad.
起码他们不用亲眼看到 自己的女儿成了个疯子
At least they never had to see the psycho their daughter turned into.
哪个女儿啊
Which one?
该醒醒的是你 我可是英雄
Wake up, sis. I'm a hero.
我从静水监狱救出了半个底城的人
I busted half of Zaun out of Stillwater
而你呢 成天醉得跟烂泥一样
while you were passed out in the bottom of a mug.
所以赶紧走吧 别逼我再打废你一次
Now can it and keep walking, before I kick your ass again.
要是离了你攒的那些破烂玩意
You wouldn't last one second
和下三滥的小阴招
without all your ugly gadgets
估计你连一秒都撑不住
and chickenshit tricks.
你不也是靠那花里胡哨的手套嘛
Ha! What about those overdesigned bitch-mittens
而且还不是你自己造的
you didn't even build yourself?
你刚才说谁是靠...
You think I need these to--?
看吧 帅不过一秒
There. One second.
要认输就趁现在
Last chance to surrender.
来啊 动手啊 大胖手
Go right ahead, fat hands.
嘿 小鬼
Hey, kid.
你没伤到哪儿吧
Still got all your insides?
可别丢下我们
But don't ditch us.
你来找我干什么
Why'd you come get me?
你根本不需要我的帮助
You don't actually need my help.
你早就不需要了
You haven't for a long time.
上次范德尔需要我们
Last time Vander needed us,
我们俩各干各的 结果...
we tried it alone, and
没成想
nothing
闯下了大祸
was ever the same.
这次
So...
或许我们可以重新来过
maybe this is like a do-over.
再说了
Besides,
他不也是你爸吗
he's your father too.
一直等着你呢
I've been expecting you.
你倒是沉得住气
Confident, aren't you?
渴望得到武器的人都有同一种眼神
It's always the same look when one covets a weapon.
我从血崖一路征战 杀到达尔莫平原
I've fought battles from the Bloodcliffs to the Dalamor Plain.
从来都没见过这么残暴的怪物
I've never seen a beast of such savagery.
论残暴 怪物可比不上人类
No beast is more savage than man.
直接说你的条件吧
I trust you have terms.
你要效忠于我
You will serve me.
我的敌人就是你的敌人
My enemies will be yours.
你的武器就是我的
Your weapons will be mine.
作为回报
In return,
你要什么我都可以满足
I will supply all your needs.
甚至尊你为德高望重的智囊
You will be treated as an esteemed adviser.
但一切的前提是你的忠心
But I demand absolute loyalty.
奉劝你不要妄为
Do not test this,
不然你会后悔没选凯特琳的地牢
or you will yearn for Caitlyn's dungeons.
你心里明白我想要什么
You already know what I want.
他不是什么怪物
He isn't a monster.
他曾经也是一个备受尊重的人
He was once a man. Well respected, at that.
只可惜卷进了一场大难
Victim of great tragedy.
他的求生意志非常顽强
He had a ferocious will to live.
忍受痛苦的能力也相当惊人
An incredible tolerance for pain.
是他让我取得了在其他实验对象身上
With him, I was able to make strides impossible with
实现不了的突破
any other specimen.
但心智
But the mind...
心智是我无法修复的
The mind I could not recover.
他的人性终究还是被兽性吞噬
The man forever lost in the bowels of the beast,
最终沦为嗜血的野兽
compelled only by the scent of blood.
我本来是这么认为的
Or so I thought.
现在看来呀 我是没有找到合适的催化剂
It now seems I had yet to uncover the right catalyst.
河床与水泡
Blisters and bedrock.
诺克萨斯为你举办了一场葬礼
There was a funeral for you in Noxus.
母亲没为我也立个雕像
Oh. Did Mother commission a statue?
我在皮城也祭奠你了
I held rites in Piltover.
她以为你已经死了
She believes you're dead.
我还真是总能让她失望
I do like to disappoint her.
你是怎么知道要这么做的
How did you know to do that?
不知道
I don't know.
只是凭感觉
I just felt...
这有点像某种谜题
It's like some sort of puzzle.
基诺 你究竟经历了什么
Kino, what happened to you?
你是怎么来到这里的
How did you wind up here?
她没有告诉你吗
She didn't tell you.
我在贝西利科认识 几个自称贵族的家伙
After a few rounds with some dubious noblefolk
一块儿喝了几杯
in Basilich,
听到了一些有关母亲的奇怪谣言
I started hearing strange rumors about Mother.
不是以前听的那些
Different than the usual kind.
他们说 许多年以前
They said, many years ago,
母亲去过他们那儿 还跟一个人
she passed through their hometown and...
有了感情
fell in love.
这可不像她会干的
That's not our mother.
谁说不是呢
Indeed.
可随着我的不断探访
But the more I inquired,
我觉得这个谣言更像是真的
the more I started believing it.
从当年的旅行日志
The old travel logs.
再到当地的记载
The local accounts.
我其实不该管的
I should have left it alone, but...
可是她跟那个男人有了孩子
The affair led to a child.
这怎么可能呢
That's impossible.
所以我们才会被带到这里
It is the reason we are here.
总之就是
Simply put,
那孩子身上一定有什么东西
whatever that child inherited is of terrible interest
让关我们的人很感兴趣
to our captors.
凭这个就能找到那头怪物了吗
This will allow you to locate your beast?
你也不能这么说
Not precisely.
我们家族保存的档案
My family archives have shed light
为这座城市解开过无数的谜团
on many of this city's mysteries.
指挥官
Commander.
将军
General.
当中有一个谜团特别有意思
One such mystery caught my attention.
德高望重的学院炼金术士 被离奇地解雇
The curious dismissal of a revered academy alchemist.
档案里只写了他才华出众
Unparalleled, by all accounts.
可是却没有提他犯了什么罪
And no mention of his crime.
这不禁让我想起了另外一个
This led to one other missing puzzle piece
让我困惑了很久的未解之谜
whose absence has always gnawed at my mind.
微光是谁发明的
Who invented Shimmer?
现在终于有答案了 对吧
We have our answer now, don't we,
李维克博士
Dr. Reveck?
你简直丧心病狂
You're a monster.
为什么
Why?
为什么要制造这些
Why do all this?
能让一个人甘愿当一个 被全天下唾弃的罪人的
Why does anyone commit acts others deem unspeakable?
只有爱
For love.
或许如果她还活着
Perhaps, in another life...
你们能成为朋友
you would have been friends.
我所做的一切
Everything I've done is
都是为了治好她
to cure her.
那头野兽应该是取得成功的关键
I believe the beast may hold the final key.
她到底得了什么病 需要你来治疗
Precisely what are you trying to cure?
我们每个人都会遭遇的痛苦
That affliction we all suffer.
死亡
Death.
我想创造一个不用再恐惧死亡的世界
Imagine a world that no longer need fear it.
- 梅尔  - 得想个办法出去
- Mel? - I'm getting us out of here.
假如这个地方是那种机关重重的迷宫
Say this is some sort of sordid labyrinth.
要是破解的时候弄错了
Usually there are consequences
通常都会受到一些惩罚
for someone who fails these tests.
甚至是致命的惩罚
Deadly consequences.
我有权知道真相
I deserve to know the truth.
当然了
Of course.
你也很好奇 为什么他们要瞒着你 对吧
Makes you wonder why she kept this from you, doesn't it?
这么多年都没有提过
For all these years?
感觉还有问题
I'm missing something.
要我说 问题就是你太没有戒心了
A healthy sense of self-preservation, I'd say.
你不是我哥哥
You aren't my brother.
你是谁 你把基诺怎么了
Who are you? What have you done with Kino?
我们对他的期望有些过高了
We had such high hopes for him.
一开始我们都以为
At first, it seemed plausible
他应该就是那个孩子
that he could have been the child.
可你母亲的种种举动
But then your mother...
让我们发现原来你才是 姐妹
led us to you. Sister.
那是什么
What is it?
范德尔留下的字条
A message from Vander.
给希尔科的
To Silco.
希尔科 我到处在找你
"Silco, I've looked everywhere, but..."
可你好像铁了心要躲我
I've looked everywhere, but... it's clear you don't wanna be found.
该怎么说呀
God, I'm shit at this.
对不起
I'm sorry.
她死的那一刻 我失去了理智
When she died, I lost my head.
我跟自己说
I told myself
我对你做的一切都是为了大义
what I did to you was for the greater good,
你罪有应得
that you deserved it.
可是到头来 我也并不无辜
But the dirt was on both our hands.
你知道去哪能找到我
Anyway, you know where to find me.
河床与水泡
Blisters and bedrock.
范德尔
V.
当初他要是看到了
If he found this,
一切可能都会不一样
everything might have been different.
得赶紧离开这儿
We have to get out of here.
是他 是范德尔
It's him. It's Vander.
那个不是范德尔
That's not Vander.
就是他 他应该是被什么东西刺激到了
It is. Something's got him riled up.
不要 范德尔 不要
No, Vander, no.
是我
It's me.
他会杀了我们的
He's gonna kill you.
别伤害他
Don't hurt him.
别
Hark!
蔚 就是他
Vi, it's him.
你就信我这一次
You have to believe me.
范德尔
Vander!
今天什么日子啊
What's the occasion?
就是美女想听老歌了 不行吗
Can't a lady just be in the mood for a familiar song?
美女不太对劲
Not this lady,
歌也不怎么搭
and not this song.
今晚
Tonight
两个不靠谱的笨蛋 一拍脑门想出的大计划
a harebrained scheme these two bozos cooked up
终于如愿以偿
to turn a dank crack
把一条不起眼的裂沟变成了一个
in the earth into a thriving, healthy community
繁荣的家园
became a reality.
今晚 是吗
Tonight, eh?
说你呢 笨蛋二号
You hear that, Bozo 2?
梦想成真了 我们做到了
We made it. We're done.
恐怕你搞错了吧
Oh, you're sadly mistaken.
我是笨蛋一号
I'm Bozo 1.
为了今晚 走一个
A night of revelations.
我有了
I'm knocked up.
是个女孩
A girl.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
其实算是一个意外吧
Wasn't really part of my plan,
不过兜里没钱的时候
but guess that's everything
出点什么事都是意外
when you're living week to week.
那康诺怎么想
What did Connol say?
没告诉他呢
I haven't told him.
还没想好怎么说
Working up the nerve.
养孩子我一窍不通
I don't know anything about kids.
光是跟孩子单独相处 我都犯怵
I get sweaty being alone with one.
嘿 你会成为一个很棒的母亲
Hey, you're gonna be a great mother.
快得了吧 我没准备好呢
Shut up. I'm not ready for that.
我正琢磨着给孩子起一个什么名字
I started trying to come up with a name,
然后我突然意识到一旦
and it hits me that this one word
决定了
is a decision
将来她就要带着这个名字过一辈子
she's gonna live with her whole life.
我没办法一边在这么个破地方 为她遮风挡雨
I can't protect her from all the shit down here
一边还要努力当一个合格的妈妈
and work out how to be a parent at the same time.
可是我转念一想
Then I realized,
我也没什么可怕的
I don't have to.
怎么说
Why's that?
这事既然你们俩已经知道了
Because the second I told you,
就别想置身事外
I put you on the hook.
你们俩必须为底城谋一条出路
You two are gonna figure this Zaun thing out.
哪怕这条出路是靠 挖河床挖得满手水泡换来的
I don't care if you have to carve it out of the bedrock, covered in blisters.
反正你俩不许失败
You're not allowed to fail anymore.
为了她
For her.
为了我
For me.
连一两个小屁孩也养不好
What's the point if we can't raise an ankle biter
那咱们也别混了
or two?
为了底城
To Zaun, then.
河床与水泡
Blisters and bedrock.
我觉得蔚奥莱这个名字很不错
I've always liked the name Violet.
? First you'll wake up in a cold sweat ?
? Come closer, will you, babe? ?
? All this hatred in your heart again ?
? I'm the one who hopes For all these things that I miss ?
? Told me feelings like this again ?
? Though I'm bitter, I can't pretend ?
? This story is over I predict the end... ?
你磨蹭什么呢
What are you waiting for?
他也是你爸
He's your dad too.
? What have you done to us? ?
萨罗
Salo?
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
杰斯
Jayce.
这问题正好我也想问你
One could ask the same question.
你怎么又能走了
How are you walking?
你不想知道是谁这么妙手回春吗
Who do you think could mend such a broken creature?
你想不想同他说几句
Would you want to speak with him?
杰斯
Jayce.
我还担心再也没有机会和你说话了呢
I'd feared I wouldn't have the chance to speak with you again.
维克托
Viktor?
其实我更愿意跟你当面交流
I would prefer to converse in person.
但我还有很多事情要做
But there's so much work to be done.
你是怎么做到的
How are you doing this?
我们上次对话之后
I suppose this is somewhat beyond
确实发生了很多事情
where we left off.
那萨罗他还在吗
Is Salo still in there?
不然我还能去哪儿
Where else would I be?
放心吧 你们的谈话内容我绝对保密
You have my solemn vow that anything you discuss
一个字都不会说出去
will be kept in the strictest confidence.
我欠维克托的太多了
I owe Viktor... everything.
谢谢你的好意 萨罗
Very kind, Salo.
我取得了不少突破
I have so many breakthroughs
正想和你分享呢 杰斯
to share with you, Jayce.
我以为你放弃海克斯科技了
I thought you were done with Hextech.
放弃我了
And me.
是我被情绪蒙蔽了双眼
I was clouded by emotions.
来吧 到我这儿来
Come. Visit me.
来看看我取得的成就
See what I've accomplished.
我帮助了很多人
I've helped so many.
你给普通人用了海克斯科技
You've given Hextech to the people?
就像你我曾经许诺的那样
As we always promised we would.
维克托真的创造出了奇迹
Viktor has truly worked wonders.
海克斯科技不是奇迹
Hextech isn't a miracle.
它是诅咒
It's a curse.
我们必须终结它 维克托
We have to end it, Viktor.
别无选择
We have to.
你好像变了
You seem different.
发生了什么事
Something happened.
我明白了
Now I see it.
应该是你也接触过奥术了
You, too, have touched the Arcane.
心智受了影响
Your mind suffered.
恕我先告辞了
If you'll excuse me,
我必须回到他那儿去了
I must return to him.
我不能让你走
I can't let you leave.
那就只能说声抱歉了
I'm sorry you feel that way.
该我说才对
I'm sorry too.
字幕翻译: 付博文 韩一旻